Miscellaneous Categories Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Miscellaneous Categories Slide Collection
1900-2005
VRC 2600
Yale University Arts Library
11
33 boxes
Collection consists of combined black and white glass lantern and black and white and color 35-mm slides. Topics include alchemy, anatomy, art movements and theory, cartoons and comics, children's drawings and book illustration, color, computer art, cosmology, fireworks, geometry and perspective, proportion and scale, graffiti, iconography, nature, portraits, principles of design, science, and modes of transportation. Also includes a section called Gumbo Mud, consisting of hitherto unidentified lantern slides.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of combined black and white glass lantern and black and white and color 35-mm slides. Topics include alchemy, anatomy, art movements and theory, cartoons and comics, children's drawings and book illustration, color, computer art, cosmology, fireworks, geometry and perspective, proportion and scale, graffiti, iconography, nature, portraits, principles of design, science, and modes of transportation. Also includes a section called Gumbo Mud, consisting of hitherto unidentified lantern slides.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by topic.
Lantern slides; Slides; Reproductions
- Alchemy (Box 1)
- Anatomy (Box 1–3)
- Art Theory (Box 3)
  - Bacon, J (Box 3)
  - Besant & C.W. Leadbetter (Box 3)
  - Blanc, Charles (Box 3–4)
  - Burden, D. (Box 4)
  - Burnet, J. (Box 4)
  - Byrne, Oliver (Box 4)
  - Cassagne, Armano (Box 4)
  - Chevreul, M. (Box 4)
  - Darwin, Charles (Box 4)
  - Depareieux (Box 4)
  - Desargues, G. (Box 5)
  - Duchenne, G.B. (Box 5)
  - Field, George (Box 5)
  - Focillon, Henri (Box 5)
  - Froebel, Frederick (Box 5)
  - Goethe, Johann (Box 6)
  - Guillemin, A. (Box 6)
  - Kandinsky, Wassily (Box 6)
  - Leadbeater, C.W. (Box 6)
  - Persoz, J. (Box 6)
  - Pico Della Mirandola (Box 6)
  - Prang, Louis (Box 6)
  - Reveroni De Saint-Cyr, J.A (Box 7)
  - Rosenstiehl, M. (Box 7)
  - Schrember, D.G.M. (Box 7)
  - Steinheil, Robert (Box 7)
  - Superville, H. de (Box 7)
  - Theosophy (Box 7)
  - Thompson, D'Arcy Wentworth (Box 7)
  - Warburg, Aby (Box 7)
  - Weber, Ernst & William (Box 7)
- Cartoons and Comics (Box 8–9)
  - Arno, Peter (Box 8–9)
  - Addams, Charles (Box 8–9)
  - Lutz, E.G. (Sketch artists sequence) (Box 8–9)
  - Art, Related Cartoons (Box 8–9)
  - Buster Brown (Box 9)
  - Dreams of the Rarebit Fiend (Box 9)
  - Krazy Kat (Box 9)
  - Little Nemo by Winsor McCay (Box 9)
  - Peanuts (Box 9)
- Comic Books (Box 9)
  - Detective Comics (Box 9)
  - Jungle Comics (Box 9)
  - Thrilling Comics (Box 9)
  - Weirdo (Box 9)
  - Wonderworld Comics (Box 9)
- Children's Drawings (Box 9–10)
- Color (Box 10)
  - Color Organ (Box 10)
- Computer Art (Box 10)
- Cosmology (Box 11)
- Fireworks (Box 11)
- Geometry (Box 11)
- Graffiti & Inscriptions (Box 11)
- Happenings (Box 11)
- Iconography (Box 11)
  - Animals (Box 11)
  - Masonic Societies (Box 12)
  - Signs of the Zodiac (Box 12)
  - Tower of Babel (Box 12)
- Light (Box 12)
- Movements (Box 12)
  - Aids (Box 12)
    - Gran Fury Graphics (Box 12–13)
    - Names Project Quilt (Box 13)
  - Art Noveau (Box 13)
  - Bahaus (Box 13–14)
  - Blave Reiter (Box 14)
  - Constructivism (Box 14)
  - Dada (Box 14–15)
    - Exhibitions (Box 15)
    - Magazines (Box 15)
    - 291 (Box 15)
    - 391 (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Box 15)
  - Expressionism (Box 15)
  - Facism (Box 15)
  - Fluxus (Box 16)
  - Futurism (Box 16)
  - Macchiaioli (Box 16)
  - Nazism (Box 16)
  - Omega workshops (Box 16)
  - Secession Group (Box 17)
  - Surrealism (Box 17)
  - Exhibitions (Box 17)
  - Exquiste Corpse Drawings (Box 17)
  - Suprematism (Box 17)
  - Vorticism (Box 17)
  - Zero (Box 17)
- Nature (Box 18)
  - Blossfeldt, Urformen Der Kunst (Box 18)
  - Haeckel, Kunstformen Des Natur (Box 18)
  - Animals (Box 18)
  - Bullflight in Madrid (Box 18)
  - Birds (Box 18)
  - Insects (Box 18–19)
  - Marine Life (Box 19)
  - Plants (Box 19)
    - Cacao (Box 19)
    - Cactus (Box 19)
  - Reptiles (Box 20)
  - Vulcanos (Box 20)
- Perspective (Box 20)
  - Alberti (Box 20–21)
  - Brunelleschi (Box 21)
  - Sutter, David (Box 21)
  - Vuibert, H. (Box 21)
- Anamorphosis (Box 21)
- Human Eye (Box 21)
- Marginal Distortions (Box 21)
- Photographic Illustrations (Box 21)
- Reflection (Box 21)
- Systems (Box 22)
- One Point-Perspective (Box 22)
- Two Point-Perspectives (Box 22)
- Synthetic Perspective (Box 22)
- Portraits (Box 22)
  - A-B (Box 22–23)
    - Baker, Josephine (Box 23)
    - Bernhardt, Sara (Box 23)
  - C-D (Box 23)
    - Cavendish Family (Box 23)
  - E-F (Box 23)
  - G-H (Box 24)
  - I-J-K-L (Box 24)
  - M-N (Box 24)
    - Medici Family (Box 24)
    - Mummies (Box 24)
  - O-P (Box 24)
  - Q-R (Box 25)
  - S-T (Box 25)
    - Shroud of Turin (Box 25)
  - U-V-W (Box 25)
  - X-Y-Z (Box 25)
- Principles of Design (Box 25)
  - Cizek, Frankz (Box 26)
- Proportion (Box 26)
- Psychiatric Art (Box 26)
- Scale (Box 27)
- Science (Box 27)
- Chaos Theory/Fractal (Box 27)
- Transportation (Box 28)
  - Air (Box 28)
  - Air Planets (Box 28)
  - Balloons (Box 28)
  - Dirigibles & Zeppelins (Box 28)
  - Lands (Box 28–31)
    - Automobiles (Box 29)
    - Volkswagens (Box 29)
    - Autos: Before 1900 (Box 29)
    - Autos: 1900-1919 (Box 29)
    - Autos: 1920's (Box 29)
    - Autos: 1930's (Box 29)
    - Autos: 1940's (Box 29)
    - Autos: 1950's (Box 30)
    - Autos: 1960's (Box 30)
    - Autos: 1970's (Box 30)
    - Autos: 1980's (Box 30)
    - Bicycles (Box 30)
    - Coaches & Carriages (Box 30)
    - Railroads (Box 31)
    - Railway views (Box 31)
    - Engines and Trains (Box 31)
    - Sleeping Cars and Coaches (Box 31)
  - Water (Box 31–32)
    - Sailing Vessels (Box 32)
    - Santa Maria (Box 32)
    - Steamboats (Box 32)
    - S.S. Normandie (Box 32)
- "Gumbo Mud" (Box 32–33)
  - Nude at the Falls (Box 33)
  - Proute Twins (Box 33)
  - "The End" (Box 33)